Guide to the Henri Chopin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Material, 1957-2007; Series VII; 15.62; (46 boxes) + 3 objects
  - Sound Recordings
    - Audiocassettes, commercially released and non-commercial
      - Works by other, unsorted
        - Poèmes de René Char, 1987 February 15; 1; 00:34:44 (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507851)
          "Crayon du prisonnier"
          "Conseil de la sentinelle"
          "Pénombre"
          "Marthe"
          "Le requin et la mouette"
          "Chanson du velours à côtes"
          "Lutteurs"
        - Gimenez, Pablo. El Coloso, 1988 December; 1; 01:00:39 (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507869)
          "Irene's Dead I, II & III"
          "Poetica (El Sueño del Coloso)"
          "Voyage sur Le Fleuve"
          "Las Catastrofes"
          "Las Indiasgalantes"
          "El Burrito Fonetico (para H. CH)"
          "El Coloso"
          "El Año Que Nacio Irene"
          "Irene Reprise"
          "Ulalume (E. A. P.)"
          "Todo El, Valle, Tribus..."
          "Fonetismos"
          "Irene - Instalación"
        - Costes Cassette "Bi Don 5", 1986; 1; 00:24:53; The program is distorted at times. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507877)
        - Sabater, Xavier. Selecciones de Poesía "Saba-Sanyo-Casio", 1992 July; 1; 00:26:55 (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507885)
          There is a booklet of poems that is associated with the audiocassette.
        - Maillard, Claude. "Sat. L. Robot", 1993; 1; 00:51:20; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507893)
        - Maillard, Claude. "Sat. L. Robot", 1993; 1; 00:51:37; A high amount of hiss can be heard on the tape. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507901)
          This audiocassette appears to be a duplicate. Duration: 52'
        - Maillard, Claude. "Mnésis", 1983?; 1; 00:55:03; The program is distorted at times. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507919)
    - Non-commercial compact discs
      Box 72 (sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Acquaviva, Frederic. "Henri Chopin: la sonore 1/2" (CDR 16), 2005 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0004
      - Acquaviva, Frederic. "Henri Chopin: la sonore 2/2" (CDR 17) (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0005
      - Barriere, Frangoise. "Ritratto di Faciulla" (CDR 7) (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0006
      - Beuvrote, Olivier. "Sons antarctiques et austraux" (CDR 8) (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0007
      - Chopin / Acquaviva. "Radio Libertaire" (CDR 15), 2007 August 2 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0008
      - Chopin / Barras. "Entretien Chopin - Barras 1. Radiophonic" (CDR 12), 2003 November 3 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0009
      - Chopin / Gaburo. "Few" (CDR 9), 1985 April 9 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0010
      - Chopin / Yterce. "Frises Majeures de Levres and Clarte" (CDR 4), 1999 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0011
      - Chopin, Henri. "Symphonie du nez et de la bouche" (CDR 2), 2005 January (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0012
      - Chopin, Henri. "Reliefs sur reliefs pour une vie reelle" (CDR 3), 2005 April (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0013
      - Chopin, Henri. "Dans le silence lance I'air" (CDR 5) (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0014
      - Chopin, Henri. "1990 - Lyon - Villa Gillet" (CDR 6), 1995 October (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0015
      - Chopin, Henri. "Frises Majeures de Levres / Staccati en Glissendo" (CDR 10), 1994 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0016
      - Chopin, Henri. "Radiophonic" (CDR 11), 2003 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0017
      - Chopin, Henri. "Performance. Radiophonic" (CDR 13), 2003 November 2 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0018
      - Chopin, Henri. "The body is a sound facory and Co." (CDR 1), undated (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0019
      - Pisek et al. "Chopin class October 2004" (CDR 18) (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0020
      - "Joncours internationale de poesie sonore. Radiophonic. CD 2" (CDR 14), 2003 (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0021
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 72)
        Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0022
    - Commercially released compact discs
      Boxes 73-77 and 80 (sound recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Works by Chopin, unsorted, (29 compact discs) (Box 73)
      - Works by others, unsorted, (47 compact discs) (Box 74)
      - Works by others, unsorted, (29 compact discs) (Box 75)
      - Works by others, unsorted, (29 compact discs) (Box 76)
      - Works by others, unsorted, (31 compact discs) (Box 77)
      - Works by others, unsorted, (5 compact discs) (Box 80)
  - Video Recordings
    Boxes 78-80 (video recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    All video recordings are VHS format unless otherwise noted
    Organized under the headings: non-commercial and commercially released.
    - "Thread of Voice," filmed by Arf Arf 18 minutes, 30 seconds, from 16mm black and white and colour, 1993; GENMSS868_0001; 1; 00:31:33 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338010)
    - Henri Chopin, Language/Poetry/Performance Conference, De Montfort University, Leicester-Angleterre, 2000 December 8-9; GENMSS868_0002; 1; 00:18:08 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338028)
    - Henri Chopin, Revue parlee, Centre Pompidou, 2002 June 20; GENMSS868_0003; 1; 00:26:20 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338036)
    - Henri Chopin, Biennales de Venise. D'art j 1997 contemporain, GENMSS868_0004; 1; 00:16:33 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338044)
    - Brigitte Cornand, Est ce que le son est bon?, undated; GENMSS868_0005; 1; 00:59:17; PAL (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338051)
    - Etant Donnes, Secam, undated; GENMSS868_0006; 1; 01:27:28 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338069)
    - In forma di Rivista - 'Ou' - Roma Weltklang, 1991 October 31; GENMSS868_0007; 1; 01:20:45 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338077)
    - Nicholas Zurbrugg, The Wonders of Dental Floss, Sound Poetry in Australia, 54 minutes, 1992; GENMSS868_0008; 1; 00:54:01 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338085)
    - Nova Production: L'Energie du Sommeil, 5' 49", undated; GENMSS868_0009; 1; 00:07:45 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338093)
    - T'as vu, All Ages Are Here, undated; GENMSS868_0010; 1; 00:39:44 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338101)
    - Weltklang, 2002; GENMSS868_0011; 1; 00:09:42 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338119)
    - Weltklang, 2003; GENMSS868_0012; 1; 00:22:45 (Box 78, Item barcode 39002102338127)
    - Berard, Stepane. Stephane Berard presente Stephane J Berard, 1993; GENMSS868_0013; 1; 00:04:25 (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338135)
    - BOBEOBI. i mpression vom ersten intemationale festival der poesie sonore berlin, 1994 October; GENMSS868_0014; 1; 00:49:25 (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338143)
    - Boltanski, Christian. Les archives de C.B., 1988; GENMSS868_0015; 1; 00:53:01; PAL (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338150)
    - Chopin, Henri. 23 presente Henri Chopin poete sonore, 1992; GENMSS868_0017; 1; 00:21:26 (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338176)
    - Ferrando, Bartolome. Performances Poetiques, 2002; GENMSS868_0017; 1; 00:22:57 (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338192)
      Performances include: 1. Shreds 2. On the inside 3. Superimpositions
    - Ferrando, Bartolome. Fragmentos (15'30"), 1993; GENMSS868_0018; This tape has not been digitized. (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338218)
    - Ferrando, Bartolome. Performances Poetiques IV, 1996; GENMSS868_0019; 1; 00:29:01 (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338226)
    - Pelieu, Claude and Mary Beach. flashes vivement notes, 1995; GENMSS868_0020; 1; 00:05:27; PAL (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338242)
      A postcard from Valentine came with the tape.
    - Rot, Max. Action inter media, 1995; GENMSS868_0021; 1; 00:05:26; PAL (Box 79, Item barcode 39002102338234)
      A postcard addressed to Henri from Michel el Valentine is included with the tape. It is dated 1996-02-14.
    - Commerical DVDs, (3 DVDs) (Box 80)
  - Other Audiovisual Material
    Box 80 (sound recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Box 81 (computer disks): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Kraft, Pierre. "Marine" / "Aquatinte" / "Attack", undated; 1; 00:30:06 (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507836)
      Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Ferrando, Bartolomé and Saavedra, Avelino. 335 pellizcos sonorous por debajo de las íes, con raspaduras de A, undated; 1; 00:24:54; Video noise is visible in the picture. (Box 80, Item barcode 39002104507810)
    - "Chopin, Les Respirations Flamboyantes", 2002 October; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002104510004)
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0023
    - "Chopin, Trilogie de 51 minutes, avec pour titre general la danse des tonneaux rouet brises, stereo 19 cm/s. production, bouche et voix HC", 2003 November, 2004 April; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002091391541)
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0024
    - "Le dernier page 1 and 2", undated; (2 DVD-R computer disks) (Box 81)
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0025; 20011.genm.47009.0026
    - "Henri Chopin Verona", 2006; (1 DVD-R computer disk) (Box 81)
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0027
    - Unidentified, undated; (1 3.5" computer disk) (Box 81)
      Copies of electronic files may be requested through Access Services: Disk # 2011.genm.47008.0028; 2011.genm.47008.0029
    - Unidentified (minidisc), undated; 1 (Box 81, Item barcode 39002091391558)
    - Studer Revox B77 MK II stereo tape recorder, 17.75" x 16.25" x 9.25" (w x h x d) (Box 125 (Art))
    - Studer Revox B77 stereo tape recorder, 17.75" x 16.25" x 8.5" (w x h x d) (Box 126 (Art))
    - Studer Revox B77 stereo tape recorder, 16.25" x 14.5625" x 8.5" (w x h x d) (Box 127 (Art))
    - Tape cutter and scissors (Box 128)
    - Grampian dynamic microphone type DP4 (Box 128)
    - Unidentified microphone (Box 128)
- Posters, 1967-2006; Series VIII
  - Posters, 1967-2006
- Oversize, 1; (9 boxes)
  - Artwork, poems, and printed material (from Series II), 1966, undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Filles du gaufrage (from Series III), 1992 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - A game for April (from Series III), 1985 April 4 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Untitled (from Series III), 1993, undated; 2 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - 11111111111111111111.000000000000000000 zéros pour un vitrail puissant (from Series III), 1992 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Mathématiques:e, nombre incommensurable qui sert de base aux logarithmes népériens (e= 2,71828...) (from Series III), 1993 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - PAN de mur orné des vitraux alphabétiques en 2000 (from Series III), circa 2000 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Jeux floraux (from Series III), 1990 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Aeschbacher, Arthur (from Series IV), undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Collet, Michel (from Series IV), 1995 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Crozier, Robin (from Series IV), 1972 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Gaillard, Jean-Jacques (from Series IV), 1972-1973 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Hobba, Leigh (from Series IV), 1991 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Martini (from Series IV), 1979, undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Nichol, B. P. (from Series IV), October 1978 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Waroquier, Henry de (from Series IV), undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Albert-Birot, Pierre (from Series IV), 1955-1968 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Bertini, Gianni (from Series IV), undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Cahn, Marcelle (from Series IV), 1957-1964 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Charmoy, Cozette de (from Series IV), undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Cobbing, Bob (from Series IV), 1975, undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Gette, Paul-Armand (from Series IV), undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Phillips, Tom (from Series IV), undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Unsorted (from Series IV), 1963-1984; 3 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Corfou, Michel (from Series IV), circa 1993 (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Alphabet pour Gratte-ciel (from Series VI), undated (Box 82 (Oversize))
  - Hommage à Christian Clozier (from Series III), 1975 (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Chemins (from Series III), 1993? (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Kafka Chopin (from Series III), 1992 (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Hanson, Sten (from Series IV), undated (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Jani, Domus (from Series IV), 1983 (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Petitjean, Armand (from Series IV), 1992 October 9 (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Rühm, Gerhard (from Series IV), 1986, undated (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - De Vree, Paul (from Series IV), 1973 (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Golyscheff, Jef (from Series IV), 1969 (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Jessemin, Aude (from Series IV), undated (Box 83 (Oversize))
  - Cadence de c (do) (from Series III), 1991 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Poème fainéant (from Series III), 1991 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - 1991: les orgues légères du blason de Serge Béguier (from Series III) (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Untitled (from Series III), undated (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Henri, Jean oui à défaut on les fait: 25 ans Jean et moi. Voilà (from Series III), undated (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Boussand, Marcel (from Series IV), 1975-1987 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Kaplan, Philip (from Series IV), 1948-1978, undated (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Minarelli, Enzo (from Series IV), 1986 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Charmoy, Cozette de (from Series IV), 1971-1990 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Haumesser, Ernest (from Series IV), circa 1962 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Zurbrugg, Nicolas (from Series IV), 1974-1991 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Posters (from Series VIII), 1967-2006 (Box 84 (Oversize))
  - Breger, Udo (from Series IV), 1972 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated; 5 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Bertini, Gianni (from Series IV), 1965, undated (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Corfou, Michel (from Series IV), 1977-1991; 2 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Guitet, James (from Series IV), 1962 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Heidsieck, Bernard (from Series IV), 1987 January 6 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Janco, Marcel (from Series IV), 1969, undated (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Maccheroni, Henri (from Series IV), 1987 (Box 85 (Oversize))
  - Cox, Ken (from Series IV), 1968 (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Higgins, Dick (from Series IV), 1967, undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Keppler, Joseph (from Series IV), 1984-1985 (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Lafabrie, Bernard Gabriel (from Series IV), undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Mousseau, Michel (from Series IV), 1989, undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Özkök, Lütfi (from Series IV), undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Smadja, Alex (from Series IV), 1960-1969, undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Gisiger, Hansjörg (from Series IV), undated (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Unsorted (from Series IV), 1966-1997, undated; 4 (Box 86 (Oversize))
  - Strange, Allen (from Series IV), 1980 (Box 87 (Oversize))
  - Furnival, John (from Series IV), 1985 (Box 87 (Oversize))
  - Corfou, Michel (from Series IV), 1991 (Box 87 (Oversize))
  - Ozalids (from Series III), undated (Box 88 (Oversize))
  - Gette, Paul-Armand (from Series IV), 1963 June (Box 88 (Oversize))
  - Unsorted (from Series IV), 1963-1984, undated; 2 (Box 88 (Oversize))
  - Ozalids (from Series III), undated (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Chopin, Henri (from Series V), undated (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Burroughs, William S. (from Series V), undated (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Gysin, Brion (from Series V), undated (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Williams, Emmett (from Series IV), 1983 (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Posters (from Series VIII), 1967-2006 (Box 89 (Oversize))
  - Chopin, Henri (from Series V), 1980, undated; 2 (Box 90 (Oversize))
  - Corfou, Michel (from Series V), undated (Box 90 (Oversize))
- Broadsides, (31 broadside folders)
  - Photographs of artwork (from Series III), 1994 (Box 91 (Broadside))
  - The London Underground (from Series III), undated (Box 92 (Broadside))
  - Empreintes sur les Andes (from Series III), 1992 (Box 93 (Broadside))
  - Spaghetti Decorated Ltd or Desdemona solid (from Series III), 1974 (Box 94 (Broadside))
  - On recherche les tueurs (from Series III), 1967 (Box 95 (Broadside))
  - Henri Chopin: Graphpoemachines (from Series III), 2006 (Box 96 (Broadside))
  - Batbedat, Vincent (from Series IV), 1990 (Box 97 (Broadside))
  - Chaminade, Jacques (from Series IV), undated (Box 98 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated (Box 99 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated (Box 100 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated (Box 101 (Broadside))
  - DSH (Dom Sylvester Houédard) (from Series IV), undated (Box 102 (Broadside))
  - Hobba, Leigh (from Series IV), 1991 (Box 103 (Broadside))
  - Hughes, Patrick (from Series IV), 1974 (Box 104 (Broadside))
  - Janicot, Françoise (from Series IV), 1963-1964 (Box 105 (Broadside))
  - Jorn, Asger (from Series IV), 1980 (Box 106 (Broadside))
  - Leonard, Tom (from Series IV), undated (Box 107 (Broadside))
  - Rougier, Vincent (from Series IV), 1991 (Box 108 (Broadside))
  - Rühm, Gerhard (from Series IV), 1985-1986, undated (Box 109 (Broadside))
  - Xenakis, Constantin (from Series IV), 1983-1986 (Box 110 (Broadside))
  - Aubertin, Bernard (from Series IV), 1969-1984 (Box 111 (Broadside))
  - Charmoy, Cozette de (from Series IV) (Box 112 (Broadside))
  - Dufrêne, François (from Series IV) (Box 113 (Broadside))
  - Furnival, John (from Series IV) (Box 114 (Broadside))
  - Gette, Paul-Armand (from Series IV) (Box 115 (Broadside))
  - Gisiger, Hansjörg (from Series IV), undated (Box 116 (Broadside))
  - Peire, Luc (from Series IV) (Box 117 (Broadside))
  - Phillips, Tom (from Series IV) (Box 118 (Broadside))
  - Unsorted (from Series IV) (Box 119 (Broadside))
  - Posters (from Series VIII), 1967-2006 (Box 120 (Broadside))
  - Posters (from Series VIII), 1967-2006 (Box 121 (Broadside))
- Restricted Fragile Material, 0.21; (1 box)
  - Computer disks, (3 computer disks) (Box 122)
    Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- September 2013 Acquisition, 1963-2007; Series IX; 1.13; (6 boxes)
  - Original works, 1963-1983
    - Henri Chopin: "Pensées sur la création," manuscript and rosewood box, 1967 September 20; (2 folders) (Box 129)
    - Henri Chopin: "Hommage à Jean Ratcliffe," dactyle poem, signed, 1983 January 25 (Box 129)
    - Aubertin: "Prix d'Excellence: Madame Aubertin de Paris - pour mon ami Henri Chopin," book composed of drawings and collages, undated (Box 130)
    - John Furnival: "Semiotic drawing. Plakat 3", 1965 November (Box 129)
    - Leo Breuer: "Bois original," with dedication to Henri Chopin, 1963 (Box 129)
    - Stephan Themerson: "Brother Francis' Lambchops," operatic score, circa 1972 (Box 129)
  - Chopin correspondence, 1963-2007
    - Correspondence, 1970-2006; (2 folders) (Box 129)
      Includes correspondence by: Roberto Altmann, Gianni Bertini, Camus, Luciano Caruso, Bob Cobbing, Francis Edeline, Pierre Garnier, Ken Gill, Raoul Hausmann, Alain Jejou, G.X. Juppiter-Larsen, David Miller, Herman Sabbe, Daniel Sotiaux, Larry Wendt, Alexandre Yterce, Nicolas Zurbrugg, and Paul [?].
    - "Henri Chopin", 1982-1983 (Box 129)
      Includes: Texte sur Armand Schwerner (1983 December 2-3), L'idée de faire des films (1982 June 27), and Résumé d'une démarche.
    - "Responses To", 1982-2007 (Box 129)
      Includes correspondence to: Frédérique Devaux (1982 June 7), Monsieur Lucken (1998 February 8), and Guy Shraenen (2007 November 04).
    - "Letters To", 1983-1984 (Box 129)
      Includes correspondence to: Amis de l'ADAP (1983 January 29), Marc Malfant (1984 June 22), and Maison des Artistes (1984 November 20).
    - "Wishes", 1966-2006 (Box 129)
      Includes cards and mail art from: Gianni Bertini (2003), William Burroughs (1970), Bob Cobbing (1970), John Furnival (1966), Brion Gisin, Key Sato (1968), and Francine Urbin Choffray (2006).
    - "Various", 1963-1976; (2 folders) (Box 131)
      Contains: a cocktail invitation from Pierre Albert-Birot (1965), an original stencil on ceramic tile from Béguier (1966), a drawing dedicated to Henri Chopin by Marcelle Cahn (1963), and drawings by Bettina [?] (1976).
  - Writings, 1967
    - Henri Chopin - Gianni Bertini: Bo de l'Air," manuscript, 1967 (Box 132)
  - Artwork, 1958-1975
    - "J'ai assis la Beauté mes genoux...," by Henri Chopin, collage, undated (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - "The New Mona Lisa," by Henri Chopin, framed print, circa 1975 (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - "Le dernier sonnet du monde", by Henri Chopin, framed poem, 1958 May 19-20 (Box 133 (Oversize))
    - "Je", by Henri Chopin, framed, 1969 February (Box 134 (Oversize))